# Laura Sofía Acevedo

#### BILINGUAL RECRUITER & PSYCHOLOGIST

+57 311 378 8538

laura.acevedo@solvogoblal.com

Medellín, Colombia

Bilingual recruiter and psychologist with experience in recruitment and human resources development, ready for the challenges that arise every day in the field of mental health. Experienced in processes of evaluate, accompany, advise and intervene in mental health; monitoring and accompanying staff in organizational, educational and psychosocial settings; approaching disabled population and psychosocial disorders. Self-driven and very proactive, great critical thinking skills and excellent teamwork abilities, with highly professional attitude, quick learning, well-developed communication and great time management.

## **EDUCATION**

Seminar "Depression, distress and suicidal ideation in children and adolescents". Cuorse Prevention of Self-harm and Suicide **Psychology Degree** 

**High School Graduate** 

2020

2019

2021

2015

Universidad Católica Luis Amigó OMS

Universidad Católica Luis Amigó

Politécnico Integral Colombiano

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Bilingual Recruiter July 2022 - Currently

Solvo Global

Multitasking and time management skills and abilities to manage social media and job platforms.

#### Assistant Psychologist February 2021 - June 2021

Alcaldía de Itaguí
Planning and elaboration of
conferences and sensitizing talks with
emphasis on topics related to the
acceptance of disability, soft skills and
parenting guidelines. In addition to

individual and family counseling.

#### Assistant Psychologist July 2019 - Nov 2019

FUNLAM.

Individual counseling, emergency crisis care, listening zone care, planning and development of support groups.

## **SKILLS**

#### Languages

- English level B2
- Native Spanish

#### Soft skills

- Time management
- Leadership
- Assertive communication
- Organizational
- Dynamic
- Problem solving
- Work ethic
- High adaptability to change

#### Hard Skills

- Microsoft Suite
- AutoCad (Beginner)
- Social Media